CLAUDIA MARGARITA FERNÁNDEZ RIVERA

claudia.rivera@tudublin.ie // +353 0830700657 // claudiamargarita.com

ABOUT ME

Award-winning multidisciplinary lecturer, architect, designer and researcher with more than 3 years' experience on creating multimedia educational material for multiple audiences across different subjects that runs her life on Excel. Looking for designing and sharing knowledge for a living.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

2021 - Present

Hourly Paid Assistant Lecturer / TU Dublin

- Engineering Computer Applications High Certificate (February 2021 present; 9 months)
- Hand Technical Drawing Undergraduate (October 2021- present; 2 months)
- Web and User Interface Design MSc (October 2021- present; 2 months)

Creating, curating, and selecting educational content to deliver asynchronous learning sessions. Delivering and planning remote and face to face laboratories and lectures. Grading projects and elaborating rubrics for assessment. Working with internal stakeholders to design and deliver lecture-lab in blended mode. Updating existing syllabus to meet learning outcomes via online delivery and to meet External Examiners' criteria. Designing and maintaining syllabus and learning material for Brightspace.

<u>Lecturer / National College of Ireland (NCI) – School of Computer Science</u>

- Web and Multimedia design Leaving Cert Summer Camp (July 2021 1 week)
- Usability Design Undergraduate (Jan 2021 September 2021; 8 months)

Creating digital content for online synchronous delivery. Delivering and planning laboratories and lectures. Leading ice breaker sessions and restorative practices to initiate and end daily lessons. Grading projects and elaborating rubrics for assessment. Designing and maintaining syllabus and learning material for Moodle.

2020 - 2021

Teaching Assistant / NCI- School of Computer Science

- Web Design and Development Undergraduate- (September 2020-December 2020; 3 months)
- Web Application Development Undergraduate- (September 2020-December 2020; 3 months)
- Multimedia Design Undergraduate- (June September 2021; 3 months)

Assisting lecturers during remote lab sessions by helping students with their lab work on Java, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Adobe Premiere Pro. Giving one on one support and tutorials to students that required special assistance.



2019 - present

Researcher at TU Dublin

Interreg EU-SHAFE (Smart Healthy Age-Friendly Environments) (Dec 2019 – Present; 1 year 11 months)

Creating multimedia tutorials for internal and external stakeholders about using digital assessment tools (excel worksheets with macros). Designing, organising and delivering online interactive co-creation workshops. Coordinating submission strategy for EU public consultation for Green Paper on Ageing. Disseminating research project on international forums and conferences.

Volunteer

- Researcher / Hands-on SHAFE (Jan 2020 – present; 1 year 10 months)

Creating animation for Hands-on Smart Healthy Age-Friendly Environments (SHAFE) logo to be displayed on their educational videos by using Adobe Premier Pro. Collaborating on desk research for "Study to cross knowledge gaps and to prepare online training packages — Research results for Ireland". Participating on brainstorming sessions with internal and external stakeholders to create syllabus for SMART module.

Course Designer / RiveraCarlos Disegno, Mexico (January 2019-March 2019; 3 months)

Designing syllabus for Inclusive Interior Design best practices for employees of RiveraCarlos Disegno. Curation of educational material to be delivered online.

2015 - 2019

Design Firm Owner

- CM Fernandez, Mexico (2015 – 2019; 4 years)

Creating multimedia material to upskill construction staff (3D Modeling Software) Designing VR tours and 3D models to communicate design solutions to internal and external stakeholders. Leading co-design workshops and participative design practices. Creating and delivering interior architecture design turnkey solutions that comply with building regulations and client requirements, focused on SME's. Project management, competitor analysis, branding strategy, budgeting, in-site staff coordination, interpersonal skills and conflict resolution to meet tight deadlines.



QUALIFICATIONS

- 2019 Present / <u>PhD on Age-Friendly E-government Services</u> / TU Dublin School of Electrical and Electronic Engineering
- 2017 2019 / MSc Human Factors / Universidad de Guadalajara, Mexico
- 2017 / <u>Summer Research Internship</u>/ TU Dublin, College of Engineering and Built Environment
- 2010-2005 / <u>Bachelor of Architecture (Hons)</u> / <u>Universidad</u> de las Americas Puebla,
 Mexico

CONTINUOUS EDUCATION

- 2021 Design Thinking Ireland (CPD 12.5h)
- 2021 W50 LSE Santander Emerging Leaders Programme (10 ECTS – CPD 50h)
- 2020 Research Integrity Social and Behavioural Sciences / Oxford Press
- 2020 Code First Girls/ Web Development
- 2019 Data Science R Basics
- 2017 Project Management,
 Planning and Control / Mexican
 Chamber of Construction

AWARDS

- 2019 Second prize Compostela Group of Universities III International Research Pitches Contest for "Virtual reality as a tool for designing inclusive physical environments"
- 2014 First place A! Diseño Don Pastor Restaurant design
- 2014 Second Prize A! Diseño for El Parrillaje Restaurant design

Software

- Graphics and video editing: Adobe CS Suite
- 2d drafting: Autodesk Autocad
- 3d modelling: Sketchup Pro, 3D
 Max
- Render engines: Vray, Shapespark for VR
- Statistical software: SPSS Statistics, Rstudio
- Code editor: Atom, Notepad ++Protoyping: Canvas, InVision
- Microsoft Office

Languages

- Spanish (Native)
- English (Fluent)
- Italian (Beginner)

